# Yenchin Lai

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen E-mail: ylai@uni-bremen.de

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research during master's program is focused on human behavior, cognition, and emotion in the field of human-computer interaction. In my master's thesis, I create a face interaction system based on empirical studies. Currently, I am focusing on affective computing, positive computing and wearable interaction in my PhD research.

## **EDUCATION**

#### PhD Candidate in Informatics

2019-present

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen, Germany Affective Computing and Experience Design

#### Master's Degree in Media Design

2016-2018

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan User-Defined Face Gesture Interactions Using Webcams

#### Language Interpretation

2015-2016

Japan College of Foreign Languages, Tokyo, Japan

#### Bachelor's Degree in Education

2010-2014

Department of Human Development and Family Studies,
National Taiwan Normal University
With extra-curricular credits at B.F.A Degree Program in Performing Arts

## **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE**

#### Researcher

2019-present

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen, Germany
Graduate School "Empowering Digital Media" funded by Klaus Tschira Foundation

#### Research Assistant

2018

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan Research Assistant in Geist project

#### Teaching Assistant

2017-2018

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan

Workshop Assistant in KMD Crash Course and Studio Assistant of Network Studio

#### Research Program Participant

2016-2017

Osaka Prefecture University of Japan

JST CREST, Research Topic: "Behavior change and harmonious collaboration by experiential supplements"

#### **Student Innovation Contest**

2016

ACM UIST 2016 Student Innovation Contest

"Most Creative Interface honorable mention" with our work "Facecook"

#### Exchange Program

2014

Osaka Prefecture University of Japan

An one-semester program studying in Humanities and Social Sciences and participation in seminars on the topic of Human Sexuality and Gender

Practicum 2013

Public Zhong Xin Daycare Center, New Taipei City, Taiwan Course credits for Practicum in Early Childhood Education

#### Cognitive Neuroscience Workshop

2013

The Tenth Annual Summer Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience, Taiwan

The Interdisciplinary Researcher Cultivation Workshop of Cognitive Neuroscience

#### INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance Translator and Interpreter

2012-2018

Japanese-Chinese-English Language Translation and Interpretation

Working mostly with companies and agencies related to music, entertainment, cultures, and design

#### Student Volunteer

2017

Unite 2017 Tokyo

Student volunteer for Unite 2017 Tokyo held by Unity Technologies

## Hackathon

2016-2017

Live Music Hackasong

A 3-month hackathon focusing on the idea of combining live performance and technology to create brand new live experiences held by Billboard Japan and Contents Innovation Program.

#### Game Music Design

2010-2011

"Crazy Festival" and "hielo store"

Music and sound design for Taiwanese phone games

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Yenchin Lai, Benjamin Tag, Kai Kunze, Rainer Malaka. 2020. Understanding Face Gestures with a User-Centered Approach Using Personal Computer Applications as an Example. In AHs '20: Augmented Humans International Conference (AHs '20). ACM, Kaiserslautern, Germany.

Lai Yen-Chin, YuanLing Feng, Kai Kunze, Junich Shimizu, and Takuro Nakao. Eyewear to Make Me Smile: Can Electric Muscle Stimulation increase Happiness? In Proceedings of the Eleventh International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction (TEI'17). ACM, Yokohama, Japan.

George Chernyshov, Jiajun Chen, **Yenchin Lai**, Vontin Noriyasu, and Kai Kunze. *Ambient Rhythm: Melodic Sonification of Status Information for IoT-enabled Devices*. In Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on the Internet of Things (IoT'16). ACM, Stuttgart, Germany.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, C#, HTML, Arduino, LATEX

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Chinese Native

English Fluent, TOEIC: 815

Japanese Fluent, JLPT: N1, BJT: J1+

German Studied French Studied